[{"id":"recwd5yAGwLV3AHWQ","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, service delivery","Subsection":"C","Questions":["reclGjy18Ovhszv3Y"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa provide any service or facility?","Answer":"Yes, as long as it is \"for the common benefit or in the furtherance of any function performed by the city\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recYkbEK2qJD5ydmW","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"taxes, income tax, elections","Subsection":"D","Questions":["rec9DiQE6bgvPShgC"],"Question":"How would an income tax be instituted in the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"Through an election question voted in by a majority of voters. As it stands, the City of Tulsa may collect income tax provided that such tax has \"been approved by a majority of the qualified electors of the City of Tulsa voting on the question at an election for the purpose of approving or disapproving of a proposed tax\". Also, it is possible for the State of Oklahoma to preempt such laws?","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recjdb1KitBoItBXK","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, taxes, sales tax, elections","Subsection":"D","Questions":["recZs9CHqvBvKgwrm"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa change the sales tax?","Answer":"Through an election question voted in by a majority of voters. As it stands, the City of Tulsa may collect sales tax provided that such tax has \"been approved by a majority of the qualified electors of the City of Tulsa voting on the question at an election for the purpose of approving or disapproving of a proposed tax\". Also, it is possible for the State of Oklahoma to preempt such laws?","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recVrEJgKdAMuw3rj","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, fees, licensing fees","Subsection":"E","Questions":["recUs51nsxk0gsqTN"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of revenue collection?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recFtDVSlpoSdA5As","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, fees, licensing fees, regulation","Subsection":"E","Questions":["reckS1G1iXA8aa7QN"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of regulation?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recO3HIAzQZHS5It4","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, special assessments","Subsection":"F","Questions":["recl88C1qi94azDuA"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa levy and collect special assessments for benefits conferred?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recArHm2PkDyCUQqN","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, debt, spending","Subsection":"G","Questions":["recW8BI6yobVdgGbs"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa incur debt?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recZ1UTclsoDNZfi3","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"jurisdiction, policy enforcement","Subsection":"I","Questions":["recBgWfp1vnLa23DG"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa enforce endorinances on property owned, leased, controlled, or supervised by the city that is outside of its corporate limits?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recuyQc1kgq9Eu1Ot","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"jurisdiction, policy enforcement","Subsection":"J","Questions":["recOA5ltx4YJJ69zq"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa exercise jurisdiction over property that is outside of its corporate limits?","Answer":"Yes, \"as authorized by the laws of Oklahoma\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recAUo3LIJHz9Z9pm","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"governance, intergovernmental relations, collaboration","Subsection":"K","Questions":["recnsxGmyRburNO4N"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with states other than Oklahoma?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"rec9UUj4uejKJZNuu","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"governance, intergovernmental relations, interlocal, collaboration, State of Oklahoma, Federal Government, Private corporations, ppp,","Subsection":"K","Questions":["rec8wvWFld0yEJnNU"],"Question":"Who can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with?","Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"enter into agreements with the State of Oklahoma; with another state or municipality; with any subdivision or agency thereof; with the federal government or any agency thereof; with private corporations, partnerships or individuals, or any combination thereof; and to exercise jointly all powers, privileges, and authority conferred upon the City of Tulsa by this amended Charter or by the laws of Oklahoma\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"reczHhaTuTmYMUW7n","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, policy enforcement, waterports","Subsection":"L","Questions":["recEBvpqZlB2vO3Aj"],"Question":"What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to waterports?","Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"acquire, plan, establish, develop, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, manage, equip, operate, regulate, and protect waterports, airports, and air navigation facilities within or without the corporate limits\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recrDWfXM8TgrKqlC","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"authority, airports, air navigation","Subsection":"L","Questions":["reciZl4VQxFZ5Pw3T"],"Question":"What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to airports and air navigation facilities?","Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"acquire, plan, establish, develop, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, manage, equip, operate, regulate, and protect waterports, airports, and air navigation facilities within or without the corporate limits\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recIJf44fLcjVyLNy","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"spending","Subsection":"M","Questions":["rec8bb7qBEZ9UefNN"],"Question":"What can the City of Tulsa appropriate and expend money for?","Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"appropriate and expend money for any public purpose\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recc3yIwRBWQvR2cn","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"After the answer, suggest learning more about zoning in Tulsa with a link to the page on zoning.","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"regulation, policy enforcement, land use","Subsection":"N","Questions":["recYLfzqYlK5TjRVy"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa restrict and regulate the use of land?","Answer":"Yes, the City of Tulsa may \"restrict and regulate the use and subdivision of land, to perform planning and zoning, and to establish by ordinance the procedures therefor\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"rec2GiJb29kOQAMIC","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"After the answer, suggest learning more about local questions, with a link to a page outlining that.","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"nuisance, policy enforcement","Subsection":"O","Questions":["recDkJkgHxnqz33EP"],"Question":"What can the City of Tulsa do to address nuisances?","Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"abate nuisances of any kind\" as well as \"assess the expense thereof as a special tax against the land upon which the nuisance is located\". As of 2018, it has been clarified that the City of Tulsa \"may summarily abate a nuisance re-occuring on the same property under the same ownership within twenty-four (24) months of a previous nuisance abatement on that property\" as well as assess the expense thereof as a special tax against the land. This resulted from a 2017 vote through which 8,291 Tulsans voted in favor of this amendment against 2,123 Tulsans voting against.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3) - General Grant of Power"},{"id":"recRzV9GFHcQO0OA1","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"See Article VI for more","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"city council, districts, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec72PZRelFTGbiNs"],"Question":"What is the composition of Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"City Council is \"composed of nine (9) Councilors elected by districts\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1) - Creation and Function"},{"id":"recYO33OmVBH5yCjQ","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, spending, salaries","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec4cV0uZuW1I6tWF"],"Question":"What is the salary of a City Councilor in Tulsa?","Answer":"$24,000 annually","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(2) - Salaries"},{"id":"rec0Qnoeo7RJZBVTE","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, spending, salaries","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recWcMxNuRrmjrQcC"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council vote to change its own salary?","Answer":"No. Prior to December 1st, 2014, this was not the case. Tulsa's City Council could change their salary by majority vote to go into effect after \"the commencement of the term of office next succeeding the term in which the change is made and then only in the event such change was approved prior to the general election for the next succeeding term\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(2) - Salaries"},{"id":"rec6socomWn37C8Wo","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, spending","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec4WnsrbE3WjjKIZ"],"Question":"Are Tulsa's City Councilors reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties?","Answer":"\"Councilors may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(2) - Salaries"},{"id":"recpk2Lp5gB9f28Yn","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recwPqzzGCjWLKXoP"],"Question":"What are the minimum number of meetings that Tulsa's City Council must hold?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council must hold at least two (2) meetings every month and these meetings must be held at City Hall.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.1) - Meetings"},{"id":"recjdtdy7L7HfQjHU","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings, special meetings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recQ4Z9ieO76kxkMi"],"Question":"Who can call a special meeting for Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call special meetings. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. This notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Finally, only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.1) - Meetings"},{"id":"recc09LDnpBCj6aSV","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["reca3D137tucbTiuV"],"Question":"How much notice must be given to each City Councilor prior to a special meeting?","Answer":"Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. Written notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call such special meetings. ","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.1) - Meetings"},{"id":"recrCgNaRAZ9MkaXs","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recU7zzXDyx9CDJrS"],"Question":"What must be included in special meeting notices to City Councilors?","Answer":"Written notice to City Councilors concerning special meetings must include the date, time, and place of the meeting. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call special meetings. ","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.1) - Meetings"},{"id":"recL7Xjal2BSCbr3a","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recoXdSTcYeBgaFQ1"],"Question":"Can subject matters not included in written notice to Tulsa's City Council be considered in special meetings?","Answer":"No, only those subjects outlined in the written notice can be considered. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. Written notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call such special meetings. ","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.1) - Meetings"},{"id":"recViCls8CGR3SyGt","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":" ","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, mayor-council relations, governance, civil emergency, meetings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recKUtQmqzyICt2px"],"Question":"Who can call a civil emergency in Tulsa?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa. During a Civil Emergency, City Council can meet for special meetings anywhere within the corporate limits of the City of Tulsa, without notice, and may consider \"matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.2) - Civil Emergencies"},{"id":"rec1HPb7olIu74sXv","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recUgUnXQxPXkyOPy"],"Question":"How do City Council meeting rules change during a civil emergency?","Answer":"During a Civil Emergency, City Council can meet for special meetings anywhere within the corporate limits of the City of Tulsa, without notice, and may consider \"matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.2) - Civil Emergencies"},{"id":"rec79OfrV2ULMlw3O","Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, governance, civil emergency, tulsa dictionary","Questions":["recXMslOU9IVA9375"],"Question":"What is a civil emergency in Tulsa?","Enterman":"Samuel"},{"id":"recSBg5R0pIJUUvl5","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, meetings, governance, open meeting laws","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recIFNsGqXbgngSEq"],"Question":"Are City Council meetings subject to open meeting laws?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(3.3) - Open Meetings"},{"id":"rechwFSnIGW1guiYQ","Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"state of oklahoma, open meeting laws","Questions":["recQWNTioQTAzS9WA"],"Question":"What are Oklahoma's open meeting laws?","Enterman":"Samuel"},{"id":"recYBwSExpE2a8oQS","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, governance, employment","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recI3uF7NibyH8ZRH"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council employ persons to assist the Council in the performance of its duties?","Answer":"Yes, Tulsa's City Council \"may employ such persons as are necessary to assist the Council in the performance of its duties\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"recHMKokNgWNxHPkR","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec4tJc3UgHGkzDvB"],"Question":"Who determines the rules and order of business of Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council \"shall determine and estavblish its own rules and order of business\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"recnV3NExpaaQSwkB","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings, disorderly conduct","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["reccTMBOeNv6A7ojy"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?","Answer":"\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"rec6dHvj2wAek4eAI","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings,","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec3gVv0sol719CIg"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for violation of Council rules?","Answer":"\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"reci6BnEK0LzSvW2r","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings, disorderly conduct","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec9WdE6TGWeb8smt"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?","Answer":"\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"rec9SA7mxbOe4me55","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recOcX2z6GYD1URAT"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for violation of council rules?","Answer":"\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"recabVVIVAtXoBIlW","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, fines, punishments","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recbvPA2CBoYJscfG"],"Question":"How much can Tulsa's City Council fine its members or other persons for a single offense?","Answer":"$100 dollars. \"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"recY1i3fmYOSQI0Ef","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, fines, punishments","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec7NZUk3vNDJrDQM"],"Question":"How much of Tulsa's City Council does it take to impose a fine on a fellow City Councilor?","Answer":"Two-thirds of the entire City Council. When each of the nine seats are filled, this means six Councilors must vote to impose such fine. \"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(4) - Rules"},{"id":"recKi8AtiNrxKjWOg","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, chairman, vice chairman","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recDI9C1Q4m6rxeUS"],"Question":"Who elects the Chairman and Vice Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council elects their own Chairman and Vice Chairman. Further, the terms of such positions are determined by the Council. Duties can be assigned to the Chairman via charter amendment, ordinance, or rule of the Council. The Vice Chairman performs duties of the Chairman under conditions of the Chairman's absense.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(5) - Chairman"},{"id":"rec8jmKbcIDkI6PYA","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/22/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, chairman","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec6AKLn5Mx88NOwM"],"Question":"Who assigns duties to the Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council assigns duties to the Chairman via charter amendment, ordinance, or rule of the Council. Further, Tulsa's City Council elects their own Chairman and Vice Chairman and the terms of such positions are determined by the Council. Finally, the Vice Chairman performs duties of the Chairman under conditions of the Chairman's absense.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(5) - Chairman"},{"id":"recsChAwABV0RmGTW","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, subpoena,","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec2k8EIZMHW2OMh6"],"Question":"Does Tulsa's City Council have the power to subpoena witnesses?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council has \"the power to subpoena witnesses and require the production of records\" for the purposes of judgging the qualification of its members.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(6.1) - Judge of Qualifications"},{"id":"recEWQxLxiJSGetAu","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, judge, qualifications","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recCESevPNO9OvkIe"],"Question":"Who is the judge of the qualifications of Tulsa's City Councilors?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council is the judge of the qualifications of its members. In doing so, it has \"the power to subpoena witnesses and require the production of records. The decisions of the Council in such cases shall be subject to review by appropriate actions in courts of competent jurisdiction which shall be commenced within ten (10) days after a final decision by the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(6.1) - Judge of Qualifications"},{"id":"recSxXDgwTIEu9ZI0","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, meetings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recOZcthnnGwf2z2t"],"Question":"How many of Tulsa's City Councilors must be present to constitute a quorum for a meeting? ","Answer":"A majority of the entire membership of Tulsa's City Council must be present to constitute a quorum for City Council meetings. Further, \"less than a majority may continue a meeting to a specific date and time. The affirmative vote of a majority of the entire membership of the Council shall be necessary to adopt an ordinance or resolution\". Finally, actions of the Council are effective following an affirmative vote of a qurom.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(6.2) - Quorum and voting"},{"id":"recY0lFILWjyxu92N","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, ordinances","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["reclF9NgSrsJW92dI"],"Question":"When do ordinances go into effect?","Answer":"Upon an affirmative vote of a majority of a qurom of Tulsa's City Council. Further, \"a majority of the entire membership of the Council shall constitute a quorom for a meeting of the Council\". However, as revealed in Section 9 of the City Charter, \"Ordinances adopting budgets, making appropriations, pertaining to local improvements and assessments, and any ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure shall take effect at the time stated therein. All other ordinances and resolutions shall take effect at the time stated therein, but not less than thirty (30) days from the date of first publication. Ordinances adopted by vote of the electors shall take effect at the time stated therein or, if no time be stated, thirty (30) days after the election. An ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure to provide for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, welfare, or safety shall describe the emergency in a separate section. The vote of at least two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to adopt any ordinance or resolution as an emergency measure\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(6.2) - Quorum and voting"},{"id":"recmP8tQuyN5MtU1k","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, city council, ordinances, voting, zoning, protests, property owners, meetings, public hearings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recDctKj7bLVOerpI"],"Question":"How can Tulsans block a zoning change?","Answer":"By convincing the property owners impacted by the zoning change to file a protest against the zoning change, Tulsans can raise the bar for the number of votes required for the zoning ordinance to go into effect - instead requiring the City Council to have three-fourths (3/4) of the entire membership of the Council to enact the zoning change. Such protests must meet two requirements. First, protests must be filed at least three (3) days prior to the hearing of the zoning change by City Council. Second, protests must be supported by either (a) owners of at least 20% of the area of the lots included in the proposed change or (b) owners of at least 50% of the area of the lots within a 300 foot radius of the exterior boundary of the territory included in the proposed change.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(6.3) - Voting on zoning changes involving protests"},{"id":"recHzCmT1NJB6v7B8","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recEkG7YSqnpQ9l4I"],"Question":"What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of general funds?","Answer":"\"The Mayor shall submit to the Council a budget for the expenditure of such funds or amendments to previously adopted budgets. The Council shall adopt budgets or amendments and make appropriations by ordinance, provided, that no revenue derived from the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax, as set forth in detail in Title 43-I Tulsa Revised Ordinances, shall ever be budgeted, spent or used for any purpose other than public safety as described therein\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.1) - Budgets"},{"id":"recOtmAvGMoCcVV9J","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["reczCm4avq1CSqz4I"],"Question":"What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of funds from the sale or issuance of an obligation of the city, or from any other source?","Answer":"\"The Mayor shall submit to the Council a budget for the expenditure of such funds or amendments to previously adopted budgets. The Council shall adopt budgets or amendments and make appropriations by ordinance, provided, that no revenue derived from the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax, as set forth in detail in Title 43-I Tulsa Revised Ordinances, shall ever be budgeted, spent or used for any purpose other than public safety as described therein\". The special treatement of the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax was the result of an amendment supported by 6,602 Tulsans. 3,640 Tulsans voted against the amendment.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.1) - Budgets"},{"id":"recpPbQeeDgWdhDYK","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations, meetings, public hearings","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recze7ORmMp2clvxf"],"Question":"What public hearings must City Council hold upon receipt of budgets from the Mayor?","Answer":"At least one public hearing, during which \"any citizen of the city shall be given an opportunity to be heard on the budgets or any item or program reccommended therein. After public hearing, the Council may adopt a budget or amendments. The Council may add, delete, increase, or decrease programs or amounts, except expenditures required by law\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.2) - Action on Budgets"},{"id":"recGWOXkVNbwDlXAv","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations,","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recnfegL8rt7wX3Vk"],"Question":"How can Tulsa's City Council alter budgets submitted by the Mayor?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council \"may add, delete, increase, or decrease programs or amounts, except expenditures required by law\" with respect to the budgets recieved from the Mayor.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.2) - Action on Budgets"},{"id":"rec3f5OzhvG9UELpF","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recmmomqhk0MJTDG4"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council establish additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets?, for the transfer of appropriations, and for supplemental and emergency appropriations which are not in conflict with the provisions of this amended Charter or with the laws of ","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may establish by ordinance additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets, for the transfer of appropriations, and for supplemental and emergency appropriations which are not in conflict with the provisions of this amended Charter or with the laws of Oklahoma\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.3) - Additional procedures"},{"id":"recwMgKY7yab2Eh2i","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, economic stabilization reserve","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recYGrUyBXjHPoqep"],"Question":"What is the purpose of Tulsa's Economic Stabilization Reserve?","Answer":"The Economic Stabilization Reserve assists to limit \"the amount of reduction required in the general fund budget during times of declining revenues\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.4) - Economic stabilization reserve created"},{"id":"recBQyKyvFr03LEjH","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/23/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, city treasurer, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recaQLFDJyoC7IIgF"],"Question":"Where are revenues in excess of the projected General Fund to be allocated?","Answer":"\"If the City Treasurer projects that total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than four percent (4%), the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate the excess General Fund revenues as follows:\n\nA. Fifty percent (50%) of the excess General Fund revenues to the Economic Stabilization Reserve;\n\nB. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated in whole or in part to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve; and,\n\nC. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated for general use consistent with lawful municipal purposes.\n\nThe Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, authorize any other available monies to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve; however, total monies in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of actual total General Fund revenues\". \"The budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization Reserve above the thirty percent (30%) cap instead to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve\". This must be conducted in accordance with the provisions of section B. However, for any of the aformentioned to go into effect, projected revenues must initially exceed $250,000, per section 7.10 of the City Charter.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.5) - Allocations to the economic stabilization reserve."},{"id":"recYTqVCkED3OBSa2","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/24/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recq94IbAD8EnVIHN"],"Question":"In what ways are the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council limited in adding money to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?","Answer":"While the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council may, at any point in time, authorize any available funds to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, the total in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed 30% of actual total General Fund revenues. When this 30% cap is met, the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve. However, such capital, other one-time expenditures, and the operating reserve must not exceed 25% of the excess General Fund revenues. Finally, all of the aformentioned allocations are only required where projected revenues initially exceed $250,000, per Sectiomn 7.10 in the City Charter.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.5) - Allocations to the economic stabilization reserve."},{"id":"reccqMX2LrXhNalmZ","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/24/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, capital, information systems, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recFLeOGgaR9kA2Sd"],"Question":"For what may the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council appropriate funds allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures for?","Answer":"The Mayor and Tulsa's City Council \"may, at any time, appropriate monies from the capital and/or other one-time expenditures allocation for capital projects or for expenditures such as, but not limited to, acquisition of equipment or information systems\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.6) - Use of monies allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures"},{"id":"recVTjmtC31O570Jx","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/24/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, capital, information systems, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recdgthAZOpFRVa69"],"Question":"Can capital funds be used to by the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council to purchase information systems?","Answer":"Yes. The Mayor and Tulsa's City Council \"may, at any time, appropriate monies from the capital and/or other one-time expenditures allocation for capital projects or for expenditures such as, but not limited to, acquisition of equipment or information systems\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.6) - Use of monies allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures"},{"id":"recj7BbeCn5BW02C5","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/24/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, capital, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recns6Po19HmY0oyc"],"Question":"For what may the Mayor and City Council use funds allocated to general purpose?","Answer":"\"The Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, appropriate monies from the general purpose allocation for any lawful municipal purpose\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.7) - Use of monies allocated for general purposes"},{"id":"recHrxqOnENuB36sb","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Suggestion":"Connect with some page on \"What to do when the City doesn't raise enough money\" OR call it \"What options are available to the City of Tulsa to resolve budget concerns when budget projections are low?\"","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, budgets, city treasurer, economic stabilization reserve","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recOmyIu0QxBEQqgV"],"Question":"Under what conditions may the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by Tulsa's City Council appropriate up to 50% of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve for any lawful municipal purpose?","Answer":"\"If the City Treasurer projects that total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will either (a) be less than the current budget year's total General Fund revenues, or (b) be less than the highest of any other previous year's total General Fund revenues, the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the Council may appropriate up to fifty percent (50%) of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve, but no more than the shortfall in total General Fund revenues as determined above, to be used for any lawful municipal purpose in the upcoming budget year. For purposes of calculating any shortfall:\n\nA. If the trigger for withdrawals from the reserve was not met in the current budget year, the City Treasurer shall calculate the shortfall for the upcoming budget year by subtracting the total projected General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year from the total projected General Fund revenues for the current budget year.\n\nB. If the trigger for withdrawals from the Economic Stabilization Reserve was met in the current budget year, the shortfall shall be calculated by subtracting the total projected General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year from the highest of any previous year's total General Fund revenues\". As outlined in Section 7.9 of the City Charter, the City may withdrawl the percentage of negative growth in the Consumer Price Index if the City Treasurer projects that the Consumer Price Index for the upcoming budget year will be less than the index for the current budget year.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.8) - Withdrawals from the economic stabilization reserve."},{"id":"rec7OXZdV7bSm9eCD","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recg0ixkhBeUqQVej"],"Question":"Under what conditions is the City of Tulsa not required to allocate any anticipated excess revenues as outlined in the allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?","Answer":"The City of Tulsa is not required to allocate any anticiapted excess revenues for the upcoming budget year as outlined in the regulations concerning allocation to the Economic Stabilization Reserve if the City both (1) made appropriations from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the current budget year and in the immediately preceding budget year pursuent to regulations for withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."},{"id":"recCnTQJqAYaNopVz","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index, city treasurer","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recXs1flaptEVIw6G"],"Question":"Where adjustments to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve are concerned, what product is the City Treasurer required to rely on when making projections for the Consumer Price Index?","Answer":"The All Items Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI-U) - or its succesor as determined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, a bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."},{"id":"recQ2V7AshgwSh9MH","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index, city treasurer","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recfjeXv4Ol0a6SKJ"],"Question":"Under what conditions are allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve by the City of Tulsa triggered by a Consumer Price Index growth rate percentage (plus 2%) rather than the City Treasurer's projections that the total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than 4%?","Answer":"When the City Treasurer projects that the Consumer Price Index for the upcoming budget year will exceed the index for the current budget year by more than five percent (5%). When this happens, the following allocations are triggered: \nA. Fifty percent (50%) of the excess General Fund revenues to the Economic Stabilization Reserve;\n\nB. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated in whole or in part to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve; and,\n\nC. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated for general use consistent with lawful municipal purposes.\n\nThe Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, authorize any other available monies to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve; however, total monies in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of actual total General Fund revenues\". \"The budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization Reserve above the thirty percent (30%) cap instead to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve\". This must be conducted in accordance with the provisions of section B.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."},{"id":"reccL19j538GHHPPo","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec1ytzgav73eUXOD"],"Question":"Are revenue changes to the General Fund caused by actions made by Tulsa's City Council or voters counted as part of triggers for allocations to or withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the year in which the revenue change is made?","Answer":"Definitely not. If the City Council or the voters take any action that changes the amount of total General Fund revenues in any material manner, including but not limited to reducing a tax or imposing a new fee, the revenue changes caused by that action shall not be counted as part of the trigger for allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve during the year or years in which the action is first implemented.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."},{"id":"recm1OZlsVsBlNNkh","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec8FmPSfA9S4pcre"],"Question":"Who is responsible for rebalancing the allocations to or withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve with actual revenue results (as state in the City of Tulsa's independent annual audit) in conjunection with the annual year-end of close of the budget?","Answer":"The City Treasurer.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."},{"id":"rec5ZiLFEq0F5HUUF","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recpZT3q1xsg1ueCk"],"Question":"In what form must ordinances and resolutions be introduced in Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"In written or printed form.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recFDXly6FTOQVZpH","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec1VN6atVxRUlmnT"],"Question":"Which ordinances must be confined to one subject?","Answer":"\"All ordinances or resolutions, except those adopting budgets, making appropriations, or adopting a code of ordinances, shall be confined to one subject, which shall be clearly expressed in the title\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"reclKGzEXFqBT0RC6","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recfNuLpuMTv1mcF2"],"Question":"Must ordinances be clearly expressed in the title of the ordinance?","Answer":"Yes. \"All ordinances or resolutions, except those adopting budgets, making appropriations, or adopting a code of ordinances, shall be confined to one subject, which shall be clearly expressed in the title\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recslOOw5TIQK8nOU","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, budgets","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["reckKaWp4EkNwUJDr"],"Question":"Can ordinances that involve adopting budgets or making appropriations involve anything else?","Answer":"No. \"Ordinances adopting budgets and making appropriations shall be confined to budgets and appropriations\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"reccYueoJds3WA3WE","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recGYfeKeg1n83sq4"],"Question":"How many meetings must an ordinance be on Tulsa's City Council agenda before it can be adopted?","Answer":"Two. However, Tulsa's City Council can waive this requirement with a vote of two thirds of the entire membership of the Council.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recWfxeXOGk90EVtM","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recJ0UrR0XFC2qPfG"],"Question":"Must a copy of each proposed ordinance shall be furnished to each Councilor or left at the usual place of residence of each Councilor prior to final consideration?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"reco0DBfcy738b3oR","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rec1ymuI0SzKyUk6F"],"Question":"Must a vote of each Councilor shall be taken upon all matters before the Council and entered in the journal of the proceedings of the Council?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recxpQC8bGuTwTUlR","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["reckwtnIsWpDL1fgX"],"Question":"What is the enacting clause for all of the City of Tulsa's ordinances?","Answer":"\"Be it Ordained by the City of Tulsa\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"reclVv1QZFmXmvuli","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recJzAooe967Ct1xJ"],"Question":"Once the Mayor recieves ordinances voted in by the City of Tulsa, how long does the Mayor have to either approve or veto the ordinance?","Answer":"15 days. \"Within fifteen (15) working days following such delivery, the Mayor shall either approve or veto the ordinance or resolution. If vetoed, the ordinance or resolution shall be returned to the Council with a written statement of the objections of the Mayor. If neither approved nor vetoed by the Mayor in the time specified, the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor. A veto by the Mayor shall suspend further action of the Council upon the ordinance or resolution for a period of seven (7) days, after which the Council may override the veto by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership, and the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor. If the veto of the Mayor is sustained, the subject of the ordinance or resolution, except ordinances adopting budgets or making appropriations, shall not be further considered by the Council for a period of ninety (90) days; provided, that the Council by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership may waive the ninety (90) day period\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recRijJMbqRqPNl3v","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recZHpStuZfLdBWcV"],"Question":"How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to overturn a Mayor's veto of an ordinance?","Answer":"2/3rds of the entire membership of Tulsa's City Council are required to overturn a Mayor's veto. Once this vote takes place, the ordinance goes into effect as if supported by the Mayor.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recgyVa2YEXEsUsSU","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recaeurItpV3zCf38"],"Question":"How long does Tulsa's City Council have to wait after the Mayor vetos an ordinance before the Council can vote to overturn the veto?","Answer":"Seven days, ...\"after which the Council may override the veto by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership, and the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recAmw5u9QGUZhH8E","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recI4GTiCISyRF6VD"],"Question":"If Tulsa's City Council fails to overturn the Mayor's veto on a given ordinance, how long must the Council wait before the ordinance can be reconsidered?","Answer":"90 days. \"f the veto of the Mayor is sustained, the subject of the ordinance or resolution, except ordinances adopting budgets or making appropriations, shall not be further considered by the Council for a period of ninety (90) days; provided, that the Council by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership may waive the ninety (90) day period\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recH0DMjb0xYKi2Xp","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos, mayor","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recEQZOozsoC3Cj7W"],"Question":"What can Tulsa's Mayor veto?","Answer":"The Mayor may veto or even reduce any item of ordinances that adopt budgets or make appropriations, unless otherwise provided in the City Charter.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recL7ZO9ltM8ztOxo","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, emergency measures","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recuDxASxgBKeY728"],"Question":"How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to adopt an ordinance as an emergency measure? ","Answer":"2/3rds of the entire membership of the Council. \"Further,  An ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure to provide for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, welfare, or safety shall describe the emergency in a separate section\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(10) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recBmy0nIGPxVmI1B","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recOqf3VDixaaq1es"],"Question":"Who's responsibility is it to attest to and record ordinances and resolutions adopted by Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"The City Clerk.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(11) - Recording and publication of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"recDipAILDoBWzGwb","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk, public relations","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recfDl46HX4vYLsU2"],"Question":"How long does the City of Tulsa have after an ordinance is adopted to be published in a newspaper of general circulation?","Answer":"10 days. \"Ordinances and resolutions shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation within the city within ten (10) days after approval. Codifications of ordinances and codes of law adopted by reference need not be published in full unless otherwise provided by the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(11) - Recording and publication of ordinances and resolutions."},{"id":"rec5Jd51Qy5nHqHDR","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk, titles, emergency measures, code of ordinances","Questions":["recvpitaSSSVzoI73"],"Question":"What is permitted to be omitted from the Code of Ordinances?","Answer":"\"Titles, enacting clauses, emergency sections, and temporary and special ordinances may be omitted from the code. Ordinances and parts of ordinances which are to be repealed by the adoption of a revised code may be omitted. A revised code may contain new matter\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(12) - Codification of Ordinances"},{"id":"rec2QN5rKbAzbptzA","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk, titles, emergency measures, code of ordinances","Questions":["reclq0b7jcBkQT7Ay"],"Question":"Who is responsible for keeping copies of the Code of Ordinances to sell to the public?","Answer":"The City Clerk.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(12) - Codification of Ordinances"},{"id":"recxkLXUyyVSdgcDn","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, titles, emergency measures, code of ordinances","Questions":["recNdX8y3jgzE5uBD"],"Question":"Who is responsible for revising and maintaining the Code of Ordinances?","Answer":"Tulsa's City Council","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(12) - Codification of Ordinances"},{"id":"recUZOoV0IQjaCg7p","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, punishments, imprisonment","Questions":["recYJpTO43OKiz8gD"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council prescribe imprisonment as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(13) - Penalties for violation of ordinances."},{"id":"rec7Xy1dNuTxZpQGI","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, punishments, fines","Questions":["recWNHr3FIOHpEz9f"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council prescribe fines as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(13) - Penalties for violation of ordinances."},{"id":"recz84mofMhULcSvO","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, punishments","Questions":["recLWuW1Pd9GAC7So"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council prescribe penalites as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(13) - Penalties for violation of ordinances."},{"id":"recbdEfc9lxTdscC5","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city charter","Questions":["recs7sGDHP8jrTAkC"],"Question":"How must Tulsa's City Council provide for review of the amended City Charter?","Answer":"By ordinance. \"The Council shall provide by ordinance for the periodic review of this amended Charter and shall submit to the qualified electors of the city amendments necessary to provide for representative, efficient, and economical administration of city government\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(14) - Charter Review."},{"id":"rec18F7cSBk7ba16Z","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, governance, state of oklahoma, authority, sovereignty","Questions":["recJWCqMOuLqKvqWZ"],"Question":"Are the legislative powers of Tulsa's City Council subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma?","Answer":"Yes. \"All legislative powers vested by this amended Charter in the Council are subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(15) - Initiative and Referendum"},{"id":"recD9Fjqa0ekN0QN6","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/27/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, administrative review","Questions":["rec1ds5meCdh84sx3"],"Question":"By what means does Tulsa's City Council review administrative actions?","Answer":"By ordinance. \"The Council shall provide by ordinance for the grant, issuance, modification, amendment, or revocation of orders, licenses, permits, certificates, and approvals by the divisions, departments, and agencies of the city. Except when otherwise provided by the laws of Oklahoma, the grant, issuance, modification, amendment, or revocation of orders, licenses, permits, certificates, and approvals shall be subject to review by the Council, upon petition by an aggrieved person, in accord with procedures which the Council shall establish by ordinance. The Council may not abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(16) - Review of Administrative Actions"},{"id":"rech7dFRMm3t2hUBB","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, administrative review","Questions":["rec3Jn0DlrFfUHiOy"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to administrative review?","Answer":"No. \"The Council may not abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(16) - Review of Administrative Actions"},{"id":"recQTLkxwWu1Q3wSX","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, public comment","Questions":["recGKUTEcX6hXBJUv"],"Question":"Concerning investigations and hearings, must City Council hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of city government?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council shall hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of the city government\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recEHXwNFGAN0jFpe","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings","Questions":["rec2t2g8O4cKwQnSa"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council investigate the conduct of the city government?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may investigate the conduct of the city government and may make appraisals, comments, and recommendations to the Mayor on the efficiency, economy, and effectiveness of administrative practices, methods, systems, and controls\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"rec2iciURmDP9LOwQ","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, subpoenas, evidence","Questions":["rec8MDgogQxyQd72T"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council subpoena witnesses as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recWMdfDSgX8XKUzo","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, oaths, evidence","Questions":["recJTBtPNNCOkfttt"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council administer oaths as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recD7uvmCs85gzSLs","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, evidence, testimony","Questions":["recfT87Zh1Ku5lapV"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council compel testimony as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recG5qLjzns8yMEse","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, evidence","Questions":["recngl4yrD4mYhHOu"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council compel the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recYWKTFnXTvpTCAo","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, ordinances","Questions":["recP19FQxiRhGq9jq"],"Question":"How may Tulsa's City Council provide the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena?","Answer":"By ordinance. \"The Council shall provide by ordinance the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recBPY7GOmfmJD6OT","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, subpoenas, evidence, mayor","Questions":["recT2hPeqmUfQsHqy"],"Question":"Who designates the police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by Tulsa's City Council?","Answer":"\"The Mayor shall designate police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by the Council\"","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(17) - Investigations and Hearings"},{"id":"recbsGXH3aOUdh1ts","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, authority, mayor","Questions":["recK3kTvH7TyMdYnQ"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances?","Answer":"Yes. \"The Council may delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(18) - Delegation of authority to make rules"},{"id":"recw7DYpf4ikRLZHM","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"7/28/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, authority, mayor, administration, appointments, removals","Questions":["reczUZZWw3qeYAUYf"],"Question":"Barring investigations and hearings, through what avenues is it legal for Tulsa's City Council or individual councilors to communicate on matters of city business with the executive and administrative service?","Answer":"\"...soley through the Mayor, the heads of each division and department of the City, as well as such other persons as the Mayor shall delegate\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(19) - Interference with appointments or removals"},{"id":"recrlApGSQpymdPlv","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, governance, authority, mayor, administration, Appointments, removals","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recUOJwJNzbczRXpT"],"Question":"Can City Councilors give orders to the Mayor's subordinates?","Answer":"Barring the City Clerk, and the City Attorney, no. \"The Council and Councilors shall not give orders to any subordinate of the Mayor, either publicly or privately; provided, the prohibitions of this sentence shall not apply to the City Clerk and the City Attorney. Violation of this Section by any Councilor shall constitute willful maladministration and be sufficient grounds for removal from office as provided by the laws of Oklahoma\". The answer to this question is sourced from documentation concerning interference with appointments or removals.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(19) - Interference with appointments or removals"},{"id":"recGQbFFz9L2lMD2q","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":2,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, city council, mayor, spending, lawsuits, claims, law","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recQzBzYvxnoI3suZ"],"Question":"How much money does a claim have to involve before the Mayor's approval and majority vote of the City Council is required?","Answer":"$1 million. \"Where a claim is asserted against the City of Tulsa seeking to recover $1 million or more, prior to any settlement of such claim occurring, whether the total dollar amount claimed is comprised of a single claim or multiple claims arising out of a single act, accident, or the same transaction or occurrence, the settlement shall be approved by both the Mayor and by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(19) - Interference with appointments or removals"},{"id":"recGQlsRcgRV5WBeJ","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recRlMXr3TV1Beksw"],"Question":"Are all executive powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?","Answer":"Yes. \"The executive and administrative powers of the City of Tulsa and any executive and administrative powers which may be conferred on the city by the Constitution or the laws of Oklahoma shall be vested in and exercised by the Mayor\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.1.) - Mayor"},{"id":"recFVcdi2byNdzZ69","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recZXSJ48gtJvgOqH"],"Question":"Are all administrative powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?","Answer":"Yes. \"The executive and administrative powers of the City of Tulsa and any executive and administrative powers which may be conferred on the city by the Constitution or the laws of Oklahoma shall be vested in and exercised by the Mayor\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.1.) - Mayor"},{"id":"rece2eXCdvV2HvsZN","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"TITLE 4 - Mayor, Auditor and Council","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":1,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"mayor, salary, spending","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["rectTWhDJZd2580bN"],"Question":"What is the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?","Answer":"$105,000.00. \"The Mayor of the City of Tulsa, Oklahoma, shall receive as full compensation for his or her services as Mayor, effective with the term of office commencing April 1, 2002, at 2:00 p.m., an annual salary of One Hundred Five Thousand Dollars ($105,000.00), payable as employees of the City are paid\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"Section 100. - Salary of Mayor. Ord. No. 20190"},{"id":"recP03LaJ4ubzuLHZ","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority, city council","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recuorLyU9kZV7L79"],"Question":"Who determines the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?","Answer":"City Council does. \"...the salary to be received by the Mayor may be changed by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council; provided, no change in salary shall become effective prior to the commencement of the term of office next succeeding the term in which the change is made and then only in the event such change was approved prior to the general election for the next succeeding term\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.2.) - Salary"},{"id":"rec8mdnIICqmmYfZY","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority, city council, temporary mayor","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recynY04rPrmnQNFl"],"Question":"Who acts in the Mayor's absense?","Answer":"The Temporary Mayor. \"The Mayor shall file with the City Clerk, from time to time, a designation of one or more officers or employees of the city, other than members of the Council, who shall in the order specified act as Temporary Mayor and perform the duties and exercise the powers of the Mayor during the absence or temporary disability of the Mayor or in the event of a vacancy in the office of the Mayor. The designation by the Mayor shall be subject to confirmation by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council. Should the Mayor fail to file such designation, the Council shall designate one or more officers or employees of the city, other than members of the Council, who shall in the order specified act as Temporary Mayor\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.3.) - Absense, temporary disability, or vacancy"},{"id":"recC6164IsraaBl3E","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recH07oybWsE7eMPV"],"Question":"Who is the chief executive of the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa. \"The Mayor shall be the chief executive and administrative officer of the city...\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recODF76gUi4eK4cG","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority","Subsection":"NA","Questions":["recK9xOfnsH7vmB5o"],"Question":"Who is the administrative officer for the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa. \"The Mayor shall be the chief executive and administrative officer of the city...\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recEljuRrFsAKzVys","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority","Subsection":"A","Questions":["recNRksASdLTkDi8Y"],"Question":"Who has the authority to establish the City of Tulsa's policy priorities?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa is to \"identify the needs and establish the objectives and priorities of the city and make recommendations to the Council for meeting the needs and achieving the objectives\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recTvFOFywAe0bI7Q","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority, authorities, boards, commissions, agencies, departments, divisions","Subsection":"B","Questions":["rec51pSVOxxEYzQHI"],"Question":"Who plans all boards, commissions, authorities, agencies, divisions, and departments of the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recaGnsE6XbLF9Fnr","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, authority, authorities, boards, commissions, agencies, departments, divisions, deadlines","Subsection":"B","Questions":["rec6HZO4BrBbedQRd"],"Question":"By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa file plans for organizing the city's government for the following year?","Answer":"According to the City Charter, it prior to May 1st.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recHGeptKIU9BWSTv","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets","Subsection":"C","Questions":["rec8UQ0uUqs2KII6H"],"Question":"Who prepares the City of Tulsa's budget?","Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa. However, per Article II Section 7.2., City Council can make changes to the budget.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"reckl4QyF8LorEFK5","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets","Subsection":"C","Questions":["rec8XeueSO3E5ZOVA"],"Question":"By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa submit the budget to City Council?","Answer":"According to the City Charter, it prior to May 1st. In 2022, the Mayor's budget presentation occured on April 20th. However, informal changes to municipal deadlines of any kind are not unusual.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recgXAwJJyz1WCcr8","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/9/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets, authority","Subsection":"C","Questions":["recaXKwMMOfVhGt2t"],"Question":"Are there tax-revenue streams in Tulsa that cannot be altered by the Mayor?","Answer":"Yes, the 2017 Public Sales Safety Tax. No revenue derived form this tax may ever be spent for any purpose other than public safety, as defined by Title 43-I.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"rectyZWJWNz3ZqVVk","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/10/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets, authority","Subsection":"D","Questions":["recdWq0G0lptcqxhA"],"Question":"Is the Mayor required to expend the operating and capital budgets of the city?","Answer":"Yes, the Mayor of Tulsa is respondible for expending \"...as provided by law the funds of the city in accord with the adopted operating and capital budgets of the city\".","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recWKnMT2wzZ9cNBV","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/10/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets, authority","Subsection":"E","Questions":["rechL0MLJ9w6E0vuo"],"Question":"Who is responsible for preserving the peace in the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"The Mayor. The Mayor is to preserve the peace and enforce ordinances, rules, and regulations.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"reckER0CBC12lmqX7","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/10/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, authority","Subsection":"F","Questions":["rechMDG6OW5MTfQ2v"],"Question":"Who has the authority to appoint, supervise, and remove all officers and employees of the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"The Mayor. Two exceptions to this are employees of the City Auditor and employees of City Council, who are appointed, supervised, and removed by each, respectively.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"rec0QQyDEckUK0PWw","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/10/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, mayor, city council, authority, boards, commisions, authorities, agencies","Subsection":"G","Questions":["recko8jYikd4mw1yx"],"Question":"How are members of boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies appointed?","Answer":"The Mayor appoints the members of all boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies, subject to the confirmation by a majority vote of the entire membership of City Council. All those appointed must be qualified electors and maintain residence within the city limits of the City of Tulsa.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recKs7LsDCg5mEtbS","Source":"Code of Ordinance","Subsource":"1989 Amended Charter","Date of Entry":"8/10/2022","Article":3,"Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, authorities, boards, commissions, agencies, residence","Subsection":"G","Questions":["recnIif0ZJsNCel53"],"Question":"Do members of authorities, boards, commissions, and agencies have to live in the city limits of the City of Tulsa?","Answer":"Yes.","Enterman":"Samuel","Section":"(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."},{"id":"recf9cdQoiDLUN4cX","Source":"Tulsa 311","Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy":"tulsa, 311, parking, violation, report, customer care center","Questions":["rec8KDL9gKmho2qUK"],"Question":"How do I report an abandoned or illegally parked car in Tulsa?","Answer":"Tulsa's 311 Customer Care Center has an online form available here  for citizens to reports cars parked illegally or which appear abandoned. Providing the exact address provides the greatest chance of action being taken. If Tulsa authorities confirm a report, the car will be tagged for towing. ","Enterman":"Dan"}]